Nathan Nguyen

Consultant at Accenture

nathanthainguyen@gmail.com

Summary

I am an experienced Java Developer, but also have a personal taste for Native IOS development. Working in many enterprise workspaces has forced practices such as test driven software development and modular code to be engrained as part of my deliverables. I have learned to be versatile by switching work from infrastructure to front end and now backend services. I have proven to deliver in a fast pace scrum environment as both a direct team member and consultant. Both sides, but especially consulting has taught me the value of pinpointing customer needs and fulfilling them.

Experience

Consultant

March 2018 - Present

Consultant at Capgemini

April 2017 - January 2018 (10 months)

Projects include developing error handling and logging frameworks in Mulesoft's anypoint platform for API's to plug in.

Client project:

Built out microservices for Wells Fargo using Spring MVC and Spring Boot that followed TDD & BDD test practices along with 12 factor principles. Implemented all validations and done testing. Microservice followed API and DDD architecture. Events defined by Avro schemas were stored on Kafka clusters. Services were deployed Nomad clusters and service discovery configuration was implemented through Consul.

Software Engineer at The Home Depot

August 2016 - April 2017 (9 months)

Involved in developing a web application to make price change requests for thousands of product SKUs in stores. Completed user stories that addressed the complete stack from Angular 2 on the front end to Spring MVC/Boot on the backend. TDD and BDD practices were enforce, by utilizing in IBM DB2 in-memory database, on all code pushed.

Selected projects include...

Pricing Adjustment & Change Management web application

Developed microservices deployed on PCF utilizing the Spring framework

- Fetched thousands of SKU product records from Oracle tables
- Utilized Java libraries to generate Excel documents downloaded from the application
- Utilized Angular 2 extensive library to consume web services and create a component-base web application

Web Engineer IT Intern at The Home Depot

May 2016 - August 2016 (4 months)

Involved in project to create an Angular 2 reusable components framework: library for future projects to be able to import through an enterprise npm artifactory. The components were written using Microsoft typescript. Utilized the event-driven model and promises to add functionality for the components.

Web Infrastructure Intern at Georgia-Pacific LLC

October 2015 - May 2016 (8 months)

Projects

- Implemented Support web page for Business Partner Portal allowing remote access for vendors and employees on production.
- Developed team's SharePoint site by manipulating DOM elements and objects from the JSOM Responsibilities include:

Enterprise Architecture

- DNS management through modifying (a-records, c-names)
- Ensured reliability by administrating development, stage, and production web servers
- Configure and deployIntranet/Extranet remote access and Identity Management solutions

IOS Software Developer at Parlore

June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months)

Projects

- Design and implement shopping marketplace feature for rollout of new patch
- Squashed bugs and refactored existing code

Worked alongside senior developers through the full development life cycle to release updates for the app. Starting with designing, I collaborated with graphics designers to produce wireframes for views, and I will go on to implement the new features for updates. One main feature I worked on was redesigning the marketplace for consumers to shop by scrolling through a beautifully presented collection of products.

Technology support at Georgia State University

March 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 5 months)

I helped students troubleshoot their technology devices ranging from cellphones to library desktop computers.

Sato Cutter at Fineline Technologies

June 2013 - February 2014 (9 months)

I worked and maintained industrial machinery for a Fineline who supplies industrial products to major brand retailers.

Education

University of San Francisco Computer Science, 2018 - 2019 Georgia State University Computer Science, 2013 - June 2017 Parkview High School, 2009 - 2013

Nathan Nguyen

Consultant at Accenture

nathanthainguyen@gmail.com



Contact Nathan on LinkedIn